

ABOUT

With over 15 years of experience, my journey took me from Paris to Montreal, and then Copenhagen, wearing many hats in my career. I don't fear change, I embrace it.

I have notably managed applicative and DevOps / Platform Engineering teams, helped some spring, and participated in transforming others toward Agile and DevOps methodologies.

Also acting as a Product Owner and Service Manager in my career, I have acquired an entrepreneurial mindset.

I am inclusive, open-minded and can bring people together which helps me resolve conflicts and help people go in the same direction.

LANGUAGES

French - Native Language English - Bilingual Danish - Learning

PERSONAL PROJECTS



github.com/baptistecabrera

INTERESTS



Gastronomy











Wine.

Whisky





Music.

Guitar

Adventure

CITIZENSHIPS

French (EU citizen) Canadian

ENGINEERING MANAGER TEAM LEAD, AGILE PRACTITIONER



Ndr Dragørvej 173 2791, Dragør, Denmark



+45 50 37 83 10



baptiste.cabrera@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/baptistecabrera

EXPERIENCE

Capelle aan den IJssel, The Netherlands Feb. 2023 - Present

UBISOFT WORLD IT

Montreal, Canada Mar. 2021 - Dec. 2022

BDC

Montreal, Canada Nov. 2019 - Mar. 2021

MATRICIS

Montreal, Canada Nov. 2018 - Oct. 2019

PSP INVESTMENTS

Montreal, Canada Nov. 2011 - Oct. 2018

LINBYNET NORTH AMERICA

Montreal, Canada Apr. 2011 - Nov. 2011

FNAC.COM

Paris. France

Apr. 2010 - Apr. 2011

Paris, France May 2007 - Apr. 2010

ARKEMA

Lavéra, France

Jul. 2005 - Dec. 2005

EDUCATION

EPITECH

Paris, France

EPITECH

Paris. France

LYCÉE A. DE CRAPONNE

Salon-de-Provence, France

Engineering Manager. Game Online Services – Remote

As an engineering manager, I was hired when the development department was growing to help organize the structure and strategy, and took charge of the Game Online Services team. The team had the mandate to create products targeted at our customers in the gaming industry (cloud-bursting scaler, matchmaker, observability platform, ...).

Development Team Lead, Network Services – Remote

As a team lead for a brand-new team, I was brought onboard to hire and manage a worldwide development team to create network products (network-as-a-service, multi-zone load-balancer, ...). I also acted as a Product Owner and Service Manager.

DevOps Team Lead

As a DevOps Specialist, I made sure to offer consistent solutions leading to continuous deployment. I helped development teams in automating their builds, configurations and deployments. I was actively involved in refactoring methods, researching new tools and helping documenting best practices to develop new standards. I acted as the team lead on assignations.

Integration Specialist & Agile Mentor

As a member of the newly created Center of Excellence in Operational Intelligence, I helped integrate solutions and applications with surveillance platforms. I also mentored the team on an Agile methodology and introduced CI/CD principles.

Senior Analyst, Production Management

As a Senior Analyst, I designed, integrated ad supported solutions and applications into the production environment and managed their surveillance. As a technical lead, I helped the team move to an Agile methodology and take its first steps into a DevOps orientation. I also introduced CI/CD principles, and acted as a lead for the team.

System Analyst

As a member of the Microsoft Systems Team, I mainly worked with automation and surveillance of applications and products we had to maintain. I helped in troubleshooting and redacted procedures to help technicians efficiently support the different platforms.

Production and Application Engineer

As a Production and Application Engineer, I helped rebuild and redesign development, integration and QA environments. I also worked at normalizing and automating delivery processes to significantly improve production delivery success rates and lay the first bricks to pave the road to continuous delivery.

Network and System Administrator & HelpDesk Manager

First starting as a helpdesk technician, I quickly ramped up and helped with system and network administration. I then moved on to manage the support team and took in charge the procurement for IT assets. I also participated in penetration tests and publications for a cybercrime magazine for the French Ministry of Defense. I was a Confidential Defense Clearance holder.

Network and System Administrator – *Internship*

I was brought up to help splitting and redesigning a network domain in two separate entities and reorganizing shared file system. I also wrote a comparative study on printing costs in a work environment.

2009 **Master of Information Technology**

European Institute of Technology

2007 **Bachelor of Information Technology**

European Institute of Technology

2004 **Baccalaureate in Electronics Engineering**

Technology Section

baptistecabrera.com